Mridul Nagpal

https://mridulnagpal.github.io | mridulnagpal07@gmail.com | +91-8179592071

EDUCATION

INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY, HYDERABAD

B.Tech in Computer Science and

ENGINEERING Expected May 2020 CGPA: 9/10

ADARSH PUBLIC SR. SCHOOL, DELHI

SENIOR SECONDARY, CBSE Percentage: 97.2/100 SECONDARY, CBSE CGPA: 10/10

COURSEWORK

Data Structures and Algorithms
Convolutional Neural Networks
Machine Learning Algorithms
Artificial Intelligence
Operating Systems
Linear and Abstract Algebra
Introduction to Databases
Artificial Intelligence*
Structured Systems Analysis and
Design
Graphics

*-CURRENTLY PURSUING

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python • Javascript • C++ • C • MATLAB • Git • Django HTML • CSS • Ruby on Rails • Jupyter MySQL • Shell Scripting • Unity •

Octave • Numpy • Keras • sklearn • Tensorflow • Bootstrap

INTERESTS

Deep Learning and Computer Vision (Implemented deep learning models like VGG net, Deep Convolutional Neural Network Inception Net and many more.)

POSITIONS

OSDG Admin, 2017-18, IIITH E-Cell Tech Head, 2017-18, IIITH Head Boy, 2015-17, APS

WORK EXPERIENCE

GOOGLE SUMMER OF CODE 2017

STUDENT DEVELOPER AT PUBLICLAB

May '17 - August '17

Made a javascript library integrated to PublicLab.A Leaflet-based HTML interface for selecting a "blurred" or low-resolution location, to preserve privacy. It also tries to return a human readable string description of location at a specificity which corresponds to the displayed precision of the location selected.

Work summary

NATIONAL INFORMATICS CENTER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Dec '16 - Jan '17

Worked with the UI/UX revamp of the intranet website for the petroleum ministry under National Informatics Centre. Used html and css to build the frontend and javascript for the backend and content managing.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

FREEDOMBOX PLINTH

Aug '16 - Present

Did a UI/UX revamp for Plinth (UI for freedombox) written in Django. Also added a new app (bind9) to Plinth.

PROJECTS

FACEBOOK AD RATING MODEL

A **deep learning** model to predict the performance of Facebook Ads, using just the information facebook requires while posting and give suggestions for imporvements.

CONNECT-4 AI BOT

Implemented an AI bot in C++ to play a Connect 4 game in 3 levels based on depth. Used alpha-beta pruning and Mini-Max Algorithm with heuristic functions.

EYE-TRACKING MODEL

Used python to create a **deep learning** model to predict where to render images/text on a webpage where the user would notice it.

LINUX SHELL

Implemented a Bash like shell in C that supports piping, i/o redirection, basic linux commands and keyboard interrupts using system calls.

E-CELL WEB PORTFOLIO

Made the official website for Entrepreneurship cell of IIIT Hyderabad using Django framework.

ACHIEVEMENTS

ACADEMICS

Received Academic Excellence Award **The Dean's List** for Academic Year 2016-17 **JEE Mains**: Ranked **405** among **1.2 Million** people.

HACKER EARTH

Ranked **27** out of 500 in a challenge by D.E.Shaw named **D.E.Code** about investment prediction using deep learning

KAGGLE

Got a **bronze medal** for a kernel given to top 10% contributors for that problem.